（スレイ）穢(けが)れが濃くなってきた
The malevolence is getting thicker.
We should proceed with caution.
（ライラ）気をつけて進みましょう
傘？
An umbrella?
ぐはあ！ うう… う…
ハァ… ハァ… はあ？
So...
（エドナ）いつまで
こうしているつもりかしら？
Are you ever going to let me go?
うわあっ…
（ライラ）エドナさん
Edna!
（エドナ）
あら ライラ 久しぶりね
Oh, Lailah. Long time no see.
それと あなた
そこにいると死ぬわよ
If you don't want to die,
you should probably move.
憑魔(ひょうま)！
A hellion!
How unfortunate.
（エドナ）ついてないわね
I felt a disturbance, so I just came to check it out,
気配を感じて様子を見に来たら―
憑魔に絡まれるなんて
not pick a fight with a hellion.
We'll ride upon the wind to follow
Your path leading far off into the distance
The answers we seek won't be easy to find
We set out knowing that from the start
We wander endlessly to leave behind records of our dream
It's worth it if it widens our map of the world
Resound, O song of the wind
Should we forgo sight, the voices of our hearts will push us forward
We aim always ever higher
Carry, O song of the wind
Should we go without hearing, the voices of our hearts will stream forth
Emitting a dazzling radiance
Your azure melody rings true
Uh, thanks.
あの… ありがとう
（エドナ）まだよ
（スレイ）え？
It's not over.
Lailah, cover me!
ライラ 援護を！
ぐう！
So he really is a Shepherd.
やっぱり導師なのね
Sorey!
スレイさん！
効いてないのか
It's not working?
It's not that.
（ライラ）そんなことはありません
ただ 穢れが強すぎるんです
The malevolence is too strong.
死んだ？
It died?
That was embarrassing,
（ザビーダ）
まったく 見てらんねえぜ
坊や
kid.
（ザビーダ）ふん…
ザビーダさん
Zaveid!
Zaveid?
ザビーダ？
ふん
ふ～ん
この坊やが
新しい導師様ってわけかい
So this kid is the new Shepherd?
Did you do that?
（スレイ）
今のは お前がやったのか？
憑魔は地獄へ連れてってやる
それが俺の流儀さ
Hellions belong in Hell.
That's my style.
He possesses a special weapon and bullets that can destroy hellions.
この方は 憑魔を葬る特殊な道具と
その弾をお持ちなのです
This thing's one-of-a-kind.
（ザビーダ）
こいつは ちょっと特別製でなあ
My precious partner, if you will.
俺の大事な大事な相棒ってわけさ
殺すことが流儀だって？
There was no need to kill it.
We could've purified it!
殺さずに救えたかもしれないのに
フハハハ… お美しい
Oh, that's rich.
I can always count on the Shepherd and his posse to be a bunch of goody two-shoes, can't I?
導師様は いつの時代も
優等生ぞろいだ
But...
だがよ 導師様
殺すことで救えるやつもいる…
Death is a kind of salvation... for some.
かもよ
What's that supposed to mean?
どういう意味だ？
H-Hey...
あ… あの…
Zaveid.
ザビーダ
I told you not to come here anymore.
もう ここには
来ないでと言ったはずよ
俺も言ったはずだ エドナ
And I told you, Edna...
I won't stop until I kill him.
俺は あいつを殺すまで
何度でも来ると
（エドナ）
私たちのことは もう―
Just...
leave us alone.
放っておいて
これはまさか… 領域？
Is this the domain? It can't be!
Malevolence can corrupt a domain this far?
領域？ こんな穢れてるのが？
It's him.
やつだ
Brother...
お兄ちゃん…
I can't believe it.
（ライラ）まさか… そんな！
Oh, yes.
（ザビーダ）そうだ
このドラゴンがエドナの兄
This dragon is Edna's older brother.
Eizen.
アイゼンだ
お前ら！ 食われたくなかったら
さっさと逃げろ
Hey! If you don't want to be eaten, get out of here now!
（スレイ）ライラ！
Lailah!
すぐに神依(かむい)を！
We have to armatize!
If he used to be a seraph, I bet I can purify him.
元が天族なら 浄化の力で…
No, Sorey!
いけません スレイさん！
You idiot!
（ザビーダ）あのバカ！ くっ…
（ザビーダ）知らねえのか？
Once a seraph has become a dragon, even the flames of purification can't save them!
実体化したドラゴンは
浄化できねえんだ
え？ じゃあ
エドナのお兄さんは…
What?! So Edna's brother...
ずっと このままです
He's beyond saving.
（スレイ）ほんとに
どうすることもできないのか？
Is there really nothing we can do?
It's impossible.
（エドナ）無理ね
I've tried to find another way, but there isn't one.
方法は探したけど
できることは何もなかった
（ザビーダ）
ああ だから俺がこの手で―
That's why I have to send him to Hell myself!
地獄に連れてってやんねえとなあ
あ… やめろ！
Stop!
Edna!
エドナ！
（エドナ）もう
お兄ちゃんのことは放っておいて
Leave my brother alone.
（ライラ）
スレイさん ここは危険です
Sorey, it's too dangerous here!
But...
（スレイ）だけど…
（ザビーダ）エドナを連れて
とっととズラかるぞ
Take Edna and get the hell out of here!
行こう
Let's go.
It's just like before.
（ミクリオ）あの時と同じ
Hellions!
憑魔か
I need the power of purification, after all.
やっぱり浄化の力がないとダメか
I can't give up.
クソッ… こんな所で
Sorey needs me!
スレイには僕がいないと
もう大丈夫
行ってくれたみたいだ
We're safe now. I think he left.
How long are you going to hold my hand?
いつまで手を握っているつもり？
あっ… ごめん！
Oh, sorry!
ハァ…
So what do you want?
で あなたたちの目的は何？
Why did you come here?
どうしてここまで来たのかしら
We followed the legend of the dragons.
（スレイ）
それは ドラゴン伝承を頼りに
（エドナ）何 それ？
Why? Did you come seeking fame as a dragon slayer?
ドラゴンバスターの
勇名が欲しかったの？
（ライラ）違いますわ エドナさん
No, Edna.
実は レディレイクに
ドラゴンが現れましたの
A dragon came to Ladylake.
（エドナ）都にドラゴン？
A dragon in the city?
それは私のお兄ちゃんじゃないわ
That wasn't my brother.
Yes, I know.
うん 分かってる
Then why did you come here?
（エドナ）
じゃあ どうして来たの？
（スレイ）知りたかったんだ
I wanted to know more.
災厄の時代って言われる
今の世界を
People say our world is in an Age of Chaos.
ドラゴンが破滅の象徴なら―
If dragons are symbols of destruction, I thought tracking one down would help me learn more.
それを追うことで
世界のことが分かるかもしれない
俺は導師になった
I'm the Shepherd now.
And I still have so much to learn.
だから 知らなくちゃいけない
そう
I see.
Well, you learned something about dragons today, right?
なら分かったでしょ
ドラゴンがどういう存在か
もうここにいてもムダよ
だから帰っ…
I think you've learned enough, so go—
Yes, I understand dragons better now.
（スレイ）
うん ドラゴンのことは分かった
But now I'm thinking, how can we save the dragons?
だから考えてるんだ
ドラゴンを…
How can we save Eizen?
アイゼンを助けるには
どうしたらいいんだろうって
ライラ この子 バカなの？
Lailah, is this kid an idiot?
（ライラ）
どこまでも真っすぐなのが―
He's a real straight-edge. It's a good thing.
スレイさんのよいところですわ
（エドナ）ハァ… まったく
Idiots everywhere.
バカばっかりだわ
Edna...
（スレイ）エドナ
アイゼンは何でドラゴンに？
Why did Eizen become a dragon?
（エドナ）知らない
I don't know.
One day, he just left, and the next time I saw him, he was a dragon.
勝手に出ていって
次に会った時はドラゴンだったわ
He was a weirdo who loved humans.
人間が大好きな変わり者だった
きっと人間と関わりすぎたのよ
He probably spent too much time with them.
I thought there had to be some way to cure his condition.
ずっと お兄ちゃんを
元に戻す方法を探していたけど―
どうにもならなかった
But I haven't found anything. It's impossible.
ドラゴンを浄化する方法なんて
どこにもない
In the end...
だから…
He was right.
あいつの言うとおりね
I have to kill him.
殺すしかないのよ
But you don't want to kill him, do you?
でも エドナは殺してほしいなんて
思ってないじゃないか
Earlier, you tried to stop Zaveid.
さっきもやっぱり
ザビーダを止めようとしてた
I...
（エドナ）それは…
（スレイ）導師もドラゴンも
伝承だけだと思ってたけど―
Shepherds and dragons were nothing more than legends, but they really do exist.
ほんとにいた
There are still so many legends which have yet to be uncovered in this world.
世界には―
まだ明かされていない伝承が
いっぱいある
There must be a way to quell the dragons somewhere.
ドラゴンを鎮める方法だって
きっと…
（エドナ）あ…
（スレイ）今のは…
What was that?
Eizen! Zaveid!
アイゼン ザビーダ
（エドナ）あ… お兄ちゃん
Brother...
（ザビーダ）ぐう
Zaveid!
（スレイ）ザビーダ！
It's them again.
あいつら…
Don't come any closer!
てめえら それ以上
近づくんじゃねえ
He's not Eizen anymore!
こいつは もうアイゼンじゃねえ
He doesn't recognize anyone!
そこにいるのが誰かも
分かっちゃいねえ
He's forgotten everything!
こいつは全部 忘れちまったんだ
All the fights we had.
散々 タイマン張ったことも
命懸けで旅したことも―
All the times we cheated death on our travels.
All the times we got wasted.
潰れるまで飲み合ったことも―
You've forgotten everything!
何もかも全部
お前は… アイゼン！
Eizen!
Stop, Brother!
（エドナ）やめて お兄ちゃん
ライラ 力を貸してほしい
Lailah, lend me your power.
Dragons can't be purified.
ドラゴンの浄化は不可能です
（スレイ）分かってる
I know that.
でも俺は 何とかしたい
But I still want to do something.
No...
いや…
I have to do something.
やらなくちゃいけないんだ
（エドナ）お兄ちゃん…
Brother...
（スレイ）いやあ！
ぐはっ！
（スレイ）う… ハァ… ハァ…
（ライラ）スレイさん もう…
Sorey, we can't...
Not yet. He's still...
まだだ まだ…
（ザビーダ）野郎…
You bastard...
（エドナ）お兄ちゃん やめて
Stop, Brother!
Stop hurting others...
もう誰かを傷つけるのは…
Edna! Get out of here!
（ザビーダ）
エドナ！ そこから離れろ
Brother...
（エドナ）お兄… ちゃん
やめろー！
Stop!
Eizen...
アイゼン… お前…
You...
お兄ちゃん…
Brother...
Zaveid...
（スレイ）ザビーダ
Hey, Zaveid...
（スレイ）ザビーダ あのさ…
I know. It's about Eizen, right?
（ザビーダ）分かってるよ
アイゼンのことだろ
あんなの見ちまったらなあ
After seeing something like that...
あ…
（ライラ）ザビーダさん
Zaveid...
But know this, kid.
（ザビーダ）だがな 坊や
I've traveled all over the world,
俺は世界中
あちこち回ってるが―
and not once have I heard anything about bringing a dragon back.
ドラゴンを元に戻すなんて話は
一度も聞いたことがねえ
But then again...
けど まっ 世界は広いからな
The world's a big place, so who knows?
もしかすりゃあ…
フッ いいんじゃねえの？
探すぐらいならよ
I mean, it can't hurt to look around, right?
Yeah!
Edna!
（ザビーダ）エドナ
When you want to give up on him,
just give me the word.
もし やつのことを
諦めるっていうなら―
いつでも言ってくれ
And I'll come right away.
そん時は すぐに飛んできてやる
That was my promise to him.
あいつとの約束だからな
Finally, one less idiot.
（エドナ）
ようやくバカが１人 帰ったようね
Edna!
（スレイ）エドナ
Okay, Lailah. Make me your Sub Lord.
（エドナ）
ライラ 陪神(ばいしん)契約をお願い
え… エドナさん？
Edna?
えっ… 陪神？
Sub Lord?
（エドナ）いにしえの契約に従い
力を貸すということよ
It's an ancient pact that allows me to lend you my power.
あなたはアイゼンを助けると言った
You said you'd help Eizen.
So I'll help you too.
だから私は あなたを助ける
You're going to search for a way to save my brother, right?
お兄ちゃんを救う方法―
探してくれるんでしょ？
うん 必ず 一緒に
Yeah! We'll find it together!
I'm counting on you...
よろしくね
スレイ
Sorey.
Same here, Edna!
（スレイ）
こっちこそよろしく エドナ
If we close our eyes now,
here on this journey with no turning back,
we can find our moments of peace
and make our wishes as we sleep
I dreamed of the world
and the hope and warmth
that our devotion can give to it
We can stop and rest
for the morrow
and together
we can laugh
I'm sure we can fulfill our duties
at the end
of this long journey
For now, let us sleep
and dream of the future
Let us walk together
Just you wait, Sorey!
待ってろよ スレイ
What?!
何だ？
What's going on?
何が起こっているんだ？
I don't believe it.
（兵士１）何ということだ
Griflet Bridge is...
（兵士２）グリフレット橋が…
Next Time
Sorey
Edna! Are you going to help me with the preview?
Of course. I'm the only reason why the fans stuck with you for eight episodes.
Edna
I need to get as much screen time as possible.
Since I'm here, maybe I should introduce myself.
Edna
Sorey
Okay, tell us all about yourself.
Edna
Fine. Ask away.
Sorey
Tell me about the Normin mascot on your umbrella.
Edna
It's a long story. Next question.
Sorey
What snack are you best at making?
Edna
Huh? I'm best at getting snacks made for me.
Sorey
What does Hephsin Yulind mean?
She stands and sits like a regal peony and walks with the fluidity of a lily.
Edna
Edna, the most beautiful woman of the century.
Lailah
Edna, don't lie!
Sorey
It can't be longer than the ancient tongue.
Edna
Time's up. Next week:
Plague Town
Edna
Don't miss it.
Sorey
So what does Hephsin Yulind really mean?
Edna
It's a secret.
Sorey
I'm gonna lose sleep over this!